# Geetika Batra

Senior Software Engineer at Oerlikon | Organizer at Learn IT Girl 791 Sector 16 FBD, Haryana. (91)8800488423 www.geetikabatra.xyz A versatile software engineer with over 3 years of experience in python, golang and java, exposure to tools like docker, kubernetes and openshift and have worked in distributed team for both proprietary and opensource software.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Oerlikon** — Senior Software Developer

February 2019 - PRESENT

- An intermediate role between CI CD developer and Site Reliable Engineer.
- Upgrading and maintaining inhouse Gitlab
- Developing and maintaining Kubernetes based cluster using ansible playbooks.
- Participate in decision making to chose highly scalable and available components for infrastructure.

# Red Hat, Bangalore — Associate Software Developer

January 2017 - January 2019

- Designed and implemented highly available and scalable infrastructure systems to deal with constantly changing requirements.
- Built a <u>service</u> from scratch following a microservice architecture, streamlined CICD workflow and testing suite for the same.
- Integrated analytics with <u>Jboss Developer Studio</u>.

# **Lyxel Labs**, Location — Software Engineer

November 2015 - December 2016

- Built a data pipeline which synced up data from elasticsearch to mongodb and vice versa.
- Built media tag server, which served html content as advertisement.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS:**

- Learn IT Girl organizer and participant.
- Accepted as an intern with Openstack under Outreachy.
- Granted Travel for Openstack summit Tokyo-2015, Austin-2016 and Denver - 2017, Berlin - 2018
- Accepted as a committee member for GHC and GHCI.

#### **EDUCATION**

**B.Tech** (Electronics and Communication Engineering) 2011 - 2015 Maharshi Dayanad University Rohtak, 68.2 %

Class XII (CBSE) 2011 Delhi Public School, Faridabad 87.2%

Class X (CBSE) 2009 Ryan International School, Faridabad 93.2 %

## **SKILLS**

Programming Language
Bash, Python, Java, Golang
Frameworks: Django, Flask,

Swagger, Behave, Tycho, RCP

**Version Control:** 

GitPlatform/OS: GNU/Linux, Mac OS, SUSE

#### **Cloud Infrastructure:**

OpenStack, Docker, Jenkins, AWS, OpenShift, Kubernetes

**Social Platforms** :Facebook Open Graph

**Storages:** Ceph, Cinder, Swift, Gluster

**App-Development:** Android and IOS